[
    {
        "question": "Who won the gold medal in the 25m women's pistol event at the National Shooting Championships?",
        "options": [
            "Heena Sidhu",
            "Rahi Sarnobat",
            "Simranpreet Kaur Brar",
            "Riya Shirish Thatte",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been named TIME's 2024 Person of the Year?",
        "options": [
            "Donald Trump",
            "Elon Musk",
            "Volodymyr Zelenskyy",
            "Vladimir Putin",
            "Malala Yousufzhai"
        ],
        "answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which English news channel won the 'Best News Channel (English)' award at the ITA Awards 2024?",
        "options": [
            "NDTV",
            "Republic TV",
            "India Today",
            "CNN-News18",
            "Times Now"
        ],
        "answer": "India Today"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country has been awarded the hosting rights for the ISSF Junior Shooting World Cup 2025?",
        "options": [
            "China",
            "Germany",
            "India",
            "South Korea",
            "Italy"
        ],
        "answer": "India"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was awarded the Sahitya Akademi Award 2024 in Dogri for the book 'Ik Hor Ashwthama'?",
        "options": [
            "Shashi Tharoor",
            "Gajanan Madhav Muktibodh",
            "Uday Prakash",
            "Chaman Arora",
            "Nand Kishore"
        ],
        "answer": "Chaman Arora"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which film won the NETPAC Award at the International Film Festival of Rotterdam?",
        "options": [
            "RRR",
            "Bad Girl",
            "Piku",
            "Lagaan",
            "The Lunchbox"
        ],
        "answer": "Bad Girl"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which countryâ€™s students won the Bronze at the Global M-Gov Awards 2025?",
        "options": [
            "USA",
            "India",
            "Canada",
            "Japan",
            "Australia"
        ],
        "answer": "India"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who from Rajasthan has been shortlisted for the USD 1 million GEMS Education Global Teacher Prize 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Mohammad Imran Khan Mewati",
            "Dr. Ramesh Kumar",
            "Shalini Gupta",
            "Rajesh Kumar",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Mohammad Imran Khan Mewati"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who won the Tata Steel Masters Chess Tournament 2025 by defeating D Gukesh in the tiebreaker?",
        "options": [
            "Vincent Keymer",
            "R Praggnanandhaa",
            "Arjun Erigaisi",
            "Wei Yi",
            "Magnus Carlsen"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the Indian-origin artist who won the Grammy Award for Best New Age, Ambient, or Chant Album in 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Ricky Kej",
            "Anoushka Shankar",
            "Chandrika Tandon",
            "Radhika Vekaria",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been awarded the Sahitya Akademi Award 2024 in Dogri literature?",
        "options": [
            "Jitendra Udhampuri",
            "Chaman Arora",
            "Veena Gupta",
            "Sushma Rani",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which two films led the BAFTA 2025, each winning 4 awards?",
        "options": [
            "Conclave and The Brutalist",
            "Anora and The Brutalist",
            "Conclave and Anora",
            "The Brutalist and The Artist",
            "Conclave and The Artist"
        ],
        "answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was honored with the 2024 Hurun Industry Achievement Award for Financial Solutions Innovation?",
        "options": [
            "Vijay Shekhar Sharma",
            "Raj P Narayanam",
            "Nandan Nilekani",
            "Deepak Parekh",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was honored with the Vishalakshi Award 2025 for her contributions to education?",
        "options": [
            "Dr. Bhagyashree Patil",
            "Sudha Murthy",
            "Dr. Ranjana Agarwal",
            "Dr. Vandana Shiva",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which company won the Forward Faster Sustainability Award 2025 in the Water Resilience category?",
        "options": [
            "NTPC Ltd.",
            "Reliance Industries Ltd.",
            "Tata Power",
            "Adani Power",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "NTPC Ltd."
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was recently awarded the Most Excellent Order of the British Empire (MBE) for contributions to UK-India business relations?",
        "options": [
            "Mukesh Ambani",
            "Gautam Adani",
            "Ratan Tata",
            "N. Chandrasekaran",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which contingent won the Best Marching Contingent (CAPFs/auxiliary forces) in the People's Choice Category during the Republic Day Parade 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Delhi Police Marching Contingent",
            "BSF Marching Contingent",
            "CRPF Marching Contingent",
            "ITBP Marching Contingent",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been honoured with the RK Srikantan Trust Award at the Sankranti Music Festival in Bengaluru?",
        "options": [
            "L. Subramaniam",
            "TV Gopalakrishnan",
            "Zakir Hussain",
            "Ravi Shankar",
            "Shankar Mahajan"
        ],
        "answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which contingent won the Best Marching Contingent (CAPFs/auxiliary forces) award in the Republic Day Parade 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Delhi Police Marching Contingent",
            "BSF Marching Contingent",
            "CRPF Marching Contingent",
            "ITBP Marching Contingent",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Delhi Police Marching Contingent"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Indian organisation has bagged Subhash Chandra Bose Aapda Prabandhan Puraskar for disaster preparedness in January 2025?",
        "options": [
            "National Disaster Management Authority",
            "Coalition for Disaster Resilient Infrastructure",
            "Indian National Centre for Ocean Information Services",
            "National Disaster Management Authority.",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which steel organization received the 'Great Place to Work' certification by the Great Place to Work Institute for the period January 2025 to January 2026?",
        "options": [
            "Tata Steel",
            "JSW Steel",
            "Steel Authority of India Limited (SAIL)",
            "Vedanta Limited",
            "Hindalco Industries"
        ],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was recently honored with the Singapore Honorary Citizen Award for strengthening India-Singapore bilateral relations?",
        "options": [
            "Anand Mahindra",
            "Tarun Das",
            "Sunil Bharti Mittal",
            "N. R. Narayana Murthy",
            "Azim Premji"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has won Best Performance by a Male Actor in a Limited Series, Anthology Series, or a Motion Picture Made for Television at the Golden Globe Awards 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Adrian Brody",
            "Colin Farrell",
            "Tadanobu Asano",
            "Jeremy Allen White",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many Arjuna Awards for outstanding performance in Sports and Games were announced in 2024?",
        "options": [
            "20",
            "29",
            "32",
            "26",
            "35"
        ],
        "answer": "32"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which veteran filmmaker will receive the Padmapani Lifetime Achievement Award at the Ajanta-Ellora International Film Festival 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Mira Nair",
            "Aparna Sen",
            "Sai Paranjpye",
            "Shyam Benegal",
            "Vivek Rathore"
        ],
        "answer": "3"
    }
]